<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Waste Guide</string>
    <string name="banner_id">ca-app-pub-7245428100570397/3095194096</string>
    <string name="btn_text_1">What is a residue?</string>
    <string name="btn_text_2">Types of Waste</string>
    <string name="btn_text_3">Final disposition</string>
    <string name="btn_text_4">Post-consumer</string>
    <string name="btn_text_5">Condition</string>
    <string name="btn_text_6">Tips Three R</string>
    <string name="btn_text_7">Profits</string>
    <string name="btn_text_8">Separation at the Source</string>
    <string name="sub_1">Solid Waste or Waste</string>
    <string name="sub_2_1">Non-hazardous waste</string>
    <string name="sub_2_1_1">Usable</string>
    <string name="sub_2_1_2">Not Usable</string>
    <string name="sub_2_1_3">Organic Biodegradable</string>
    <string name="sub_2_2">Hazardous and Special Waste</string>
    <string name="sub_2_2_1">Dangerous</string>
    <string name="sub_2_2_2">Specials</string>
    <string name="sub_4_1">These are Post-consumer products</string>
    <string name="sub_6_1">Reduce</string>
    <string name="sub_6_2">Re-use</string>
    <string name="sub_6_3">Recycle</string>
    <string name="sub_8_1">White trash can</string>
    <string name="sub_8_2">Green trash can</string>
    <string name="sub_8_3">Black trash can</string>
    <string name="info_1">It is any object, material, substance or solid element resulting from the consumption or use of a good in domestic, industrial, commercial, institutional, service activities, that the generator abandons, rejects or delivers and that is capable of being used or transformed into a new well, with economic or final disposal value. Solid waste is divided into usable and non-usable.</string>
    <string name="info_2_1_1">Any material, object, substance or element that has no value for the person who generates it, but can be incorporated back into a production process.</string>
    <string name="info_2_1_2">Any material or substance that does not offer any possibility of use, reuse or reincorporation to a production process. They have no commercial value, therefore they require final disposal.</string>
    <string name="info_2_1_3">They are those that have the characteristic of being able to disintegrate or degrade quickly, transforming into another type of organic matter. Example: The remains of food, fruit, husks, meat, eggs.</string>
    <string name="info_2_2_1">It is that residue or waste that due to its corrosive, reactive, explosive, toxic, flammable, infectious or radioactive characteristics can cause a risk to human health and the environment. Likewise, containers, packages or packaging that have been in contact with them are considered hazardous waste or waste.</string>
    <string name="info_2_2_2">Solid waste that, due to its quality, quantity, magnitude, volume or weight can present dangers and, therefore, requires special handling. It includes waste with expired consumption periods, waste from establishments that use dangerous substances, sludge, bulky or heavy waste that, with authorization or illegally, are managed together with municipal solid waste.</string>
    <string name="info_3_1">It is the place technically selected, designed and operated for the controlled final disposal of solid waste, without causing danger, damage or risk to public health, minimizing and controlling environmental impacts and using engineering principles, for the confinement and isolation of waste solids in a minimum area, with compaction of waste, daily coverage of the same, control of gases and leachate, and final coverage.</string>
    <string name="info_4_1">Post-consumption is an environmental task that consists of delivering hazardous and special waste to manufacturing companies through the post-consumer program in order to guarantee its proper collection, treatment and final disposal.</string>
    <string name="info_4_2">It must be taken into account that post-consumer waste must be separated from ordinary waste and managed in an environmentally appropriate way. For this there are collecting companies such as Lúmin (bulbs and fluorescent tubes), Recoenergy (lead acid battery), Recopila y Batteries with the environment (domestic batteries), Green Network and Eco Computo (electronic devices), Blue Point (medicines) among others. , which have specialized containers to collect this waste and we can find it in chain stores, drug stores, state entities or at the same points of sale.</string>
    <string name="info_5_1">To make the separation from the source of solid waste, it is necessary to separate it in such a way that it is not contaminated with other waste, being essential that the materials are always clean and dry.</string>
    <string name="info_5_1_1">In the case of containers containing liquids, it is advisable to drain to avoid spilling its content on other materials.</string>
    <string name="info_5_1_2">Glass or plastic containers that store chemicals or that were in contact with them should not be disposed of with the usable material, since they are considered hazardous waste.</string>
    <string name="info_5_1_3">Papers impregnated with paraffin, black smoke, grease, oil, plastic coating, satin finish and aluminum are harmful to the recycling process and can contaminate other materials.</string>
    <string name="info_6_1">It implies reducing the production of garbage, which means that when acquiring a product it must be strictly necessary, as well as requiring objects that have few wrapping or packaging, avoiding those elements that will soon become garbage.</string>
    <string name="info_6_1_1">- Use products that have a minimum of packaging.</string>
    <string name="info_6_1_2">- Avoid the purchase and use of disposables.</string>
    <string name="info_6_1_3">- Use washable containers for food, and thermos for drinks.</string>
    <string name="info_6_1_4">- Use rechargeable batteries.</string>
    <string name="info_6_1_5">- Avoid containers made of mixed materials.</string>
    <string name="info_6_2">It involves making the most of the waste that is thrown (plastic bags, containers, disposables, clothing, etc.), using waste as an essential material for the development of new products, in order to reduce waste, like many of these. The products could be reused again in different ways.</string>
    <string name="info_6_2_1">- Reuse plastic containers or any type of elements giving a new utility.</string>
    <string name="info_6_2_2">- Use the sheets of paper on both sides.</string>
    <string name="info_6_2_3">- Repair deteriorated or damaged items, preventing them from being thrown away.</string>
    <string name="info_6_2_4">- Giving away items that you no longer use to other people "one person's trash is another's treasure."</string>
    <string name="info_6_3">It is the process by which the recovered solid waste is used and transformed and its potential for reincorporation is returned to the materials as raw material for the manufacture of new products.</string>
    <string name="info_6_3_1">- Carry out the adequate separation of waste at the source.</string>
    <string name="info_6_3_2">- Instill others to practice separation at the source.</string>
    <string name="info_7_1">We contribute to the preservation of the environment by reducing the amount of waste that is sent to the sanitary landfill, lowering the levels of contamination caused by solid waste.</string>
    <string name="info_7_2">It reduces the use of non-renewable resources such as fossil fuels and minerals used for the generation of plastics, glass, aluminum, among others. As well as renewables such as trees for the manufacture of paper and water, it is used in most industrial processes.</string>
    <string name="info_7_3">It gives an economic value to the waste we generate, since it costs less to recycle than to manufacture a new product. By recycling we save water, energy and raw materials.</string>
    <string name="info_7_4">Recycling can promote many jobs, since a large workforce is needed to collect and classify materials suitable for use, generating income for many families and improving their socioeconomic conditions.</string>
    <string name="info_8_1">It is the action of classifying the waste in bags or containers at the generation site for its subsequent handling, either for use or final disposal.</string>
    <string name="info_8_1_1">Cardboard and paper (sheets, folding, newspaper, folders), Glass (Bottles, containers), Plastics (bags, PET containers, lids), Metal waste (scrap, lids, containers), Tetrapak composite packaging (milk boxes, juice boxes , liquor boxes).</string>
    <string name="info_8_1_2">Tissue paper (toilet paper, wet cloths, diapers, hand towels, sanitary napkins, panty liners), Waxed, laminated and metallized papers, Ceramics, Flat glass, Bones, Sweeping material, Cigarette butts, Dirty packaging and packaging materials , Cooked food scraps.</string>
    <string name="info_8_1_3">Uncooked food waste, Cutting and pruning of plant materials, Leaf litter</string>
    <string name="pregunta_1_cv">What is a usable organic waste?</string>
    <string name="r_1_1_cv">They are materials resulting from the sweeping of the streets.</string>
    <string name="r_1_2_cv">Element that quickly decomposes and becomes organic matter.</string>
    <string name="r_1_3_cv">Material or utility object that does not offer any utility.</string>
    <string name="r_1_4_cv">Material or object that we dispose of, but can be recycled.</string>
    <string name="pregunta_2_cv">What do the three R\'s stand for?</string>
    <string name="r_2_1_cv">Reduce, reuse, recycle.</string>
    <string name="r_2_2_cv">Repair, recycle, collect.</string>
    <string name="r_2_3_cv">Reduce, rescue, reuse.</string>
    <string name="r_2_4_cv">None of the above.</string>
    <string name="pregunta_3_cv">Isn\'t it a usable organic waste?</string>
    <string name="r_3_1_cv">Banana peels.</string>
    <string name="r_3_2_cv">Cooked food waste.</string>
    <string name="r_3_3_cv">Eggshell.</string>
    <string name="r_3_4_cv">Pasture.</string>
    <string name="pregunta_1_cb">What is a usable waste?</string>
    <string name="r_1_1_cb">Material or object that does not offer any utility.</string>
    <string name="r_1_2_cb">Material or object that we dispose of, but that can be recycled.</string>
    <string name="r_1_3_cb">Any material that pollutes the environment.</string>
    <string name="r_1_4_cb">They are large items.</string>
    <string name="pregunta_2_cb">A condition to deliver a usable material is?</string>
    <string name="r_2_1_cb">Which are impregnated with grease and oil.</string>
    <string name="r_2_2_cb">Wash them.</string>
    <string name="r_2_3_cb">Clean and dry.</string>
    <string name="r_2_4_cb">Do not drain.</string>
    <string name="pregunta_3_cb">Does a post-consumer waste have to be disposed of in the white trash can?</string>
    <string name="r_3_1_cb">Yes.</string>
    <string name="r_3_2_cb">Not.</string>
    <string name="r_3_3_cb">Just the drugs.</string>
    <string name="r_3_4_cb">Just the bulbs.</string>
    <string name="pregunta_1_cn">What is unusable waste?</string>
    <string name="r_1_1_cn">Element that quickly decomposes and becomes organic matter.</string>
    <string name="r_1_2_cn">They are large items.</string>
    <string name="r_1_3_cn">Material or object that does not offer any utility.</string>
    <string name="r_1_4_cn">Material or object that we dispose of, but that can be recycled.</string>
    <string name="pregunta_2_cn">What types of waste should go directly to a landfill?</string>
    <string name="r_2_1_cn">Hazardous waste.</string>
    <string name="r_2_2_cn">Unusable waste.</string>
    <string name="r_2_3_cn">Usable waste.</string>
    <string name="r_2_4_cn">Organic waste.</string>
    <string name="pregunta_3_cn">How long does it take for a plastic bottle to degrade on average?</string>
    <string name="r_3_1_cn">Less than a year.</string>
    <string name="r_3_2_cn">Between 1 to 10 years.</string>
    <string name="r_3_3_cn">Between 10 to 100 years.</string>
    <string name="r_3_4_cn">Between 100 to 1000 years.</string>
    <string name="p_1">QUESTION 1</string>
    <string name="p_2">QUESTION 2</string>
    <string name="p_3">QUESTION 3</string>
    <string name="encabezado">RESULTS</string>
    <string name="next">NEXT</string>
</resources>